Guide to the William V. Ballew, Jr. papers, 1965-1968 MS 254
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
William V. Ballew, Jr. papers
1965-1968
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Ballew, William V., Jr.
MS 254
1.5 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
The collection consists of William V. Ballew, Jr.'s workpapers, correspondence, minutes, and news clippings relating to the Houston-Harris County Economic Opportunity Organization. William V. Ballew, Jr., a Houston attorney, served as Chairman, Board of Trustees, Houston-Harris County Economic Opportunities Committee, an organization that initiated welfare programs as part of President Lyndon Johnson's War on Poverty.
Biographical Note
William V. Ballew, Jr., a Houston attorney, served as Chairman, Board of Trustees, Houston-Harris County Economic Opportunities Committee, an organization that initiated welfare programs as part of President Lyndon Johnson's War on Poverty. He was born in Abilene, Texas in 1928, attended Rice University, and served in the US Navy during world War II. He was co-chairman of President Johnson's 1964 election campaign in Harris County and throughout much of the 1960s and 1970s was also active with the Texas Bill of Rights Foundation, a group dedicated to the debate and discussion of public issues.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of Ballew's workpapers, correspondence, minutes, and news clippings relating to the Houston-Harris County Economic Opportunity Organization.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research. Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Acquisition Information
Gift of William V. Ballew, March 1977.
Index Terms
Subjects
Civil rights; Civil rights -- Texas; Business
Document Types
letters (correspondence); minutes (administrative records); clippings (information artifacts); speeches
- Series I: Houston-Harris County Economic Opportunity Organization, 46129
  - Correspondence: January – June, 1966, 46144 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: July – September 1966, 46143 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: October – December 1966, 46142 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: January – February 1967, 46141 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: March – July 1967, 46140 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence and Memos re: Membership, 1966-1967, 46139 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes: 1965 – 1966, 46138 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Minutes: 1966, 46137 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Minutes: January – April 1967, 46136 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Minutes: May – July 1967, 46135 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Minutes: 1967, 46134 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Finance Committee: 1966 – 1967, 46133 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Legal Services Program, 46132 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Program Proposals, 1965 – 1967, 46131 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Additional Memoranda, 1965 - 1967, 46130 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Series II: Anti-Poverty and other campaigns, 46122
  - Anti-poverty material and speeches, 1965 – 1966, 46128 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Anti-Poverty News Clippings, 1965 – 1966, 46127 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Anti-Poverty News Clippings, 1967 – 1968, 46126 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Economic Opportunity Workpapers, February – June 1965, 46125 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Economic Opportunity Workpapers, July – December 1965, 46124 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Houston Action for Youth, 1965 – 1967, 46123 (Box 2, Folder 6)